<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<XPAGES>
  <INFORMATIONS>
    <LABEL>daxe</LABEL>
    <TITRE>Daxe</TITRE>
    <LOGO fichier="icon.png"/>
    <INTERFACE>nuages</INTERFACE>
    <LANGUE>en</LANGUE>
  </INFORMATIONS>
  
  <PAGE label="index" titre="Index">
    <SECTION titre="Daxe">
      <PARAGRAPHE>Daxe is an XML editor for the web. It works in the same way as <LIENWEB url="http://jaxe.sourceforge.net/en/">Jaxe</LIENWEB>, using an XML schema and a configuration file to define the XML language and the editor UI. A number of common element displays are provided with Daxe to make it easy to create a new editor UI for any XML language.</PARAGRAPHE>
      <PARAGRAPHE>Daxe is written in <LIENWEB url="https://www.dartlang.org/">Dart</LIENWEB>, which is transformed into Javascript to work in modern web browsers (it does not work on IE before version 9). As with any Javascript application, it works without the need for a plugin.</PARAGRAPHE>
      <PARAGRAPHE>In itself, Daxe is not very useful, because it cannot open or save a local file (because of browser restrictions). It needs to be either used with the <LIENWEB url="https://github.com/adopt/daxapp">Daxe desktop application</LIENWEB>, or included into a larger system like a CMS. Daxe is now integrated into <LIENWEB url="http://media4.obspm.fr/outils/webjaxe/en/">WebJaxe</LIENWEB>, and will soon be used in <LIENWEB url="http://www.lon-capa.org/">LON-CAPA</LIENWEB>.</PARAGRAPHE>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION titre="Licence">
      <PARAGRAPHE>Daxe is licenced under the <LIENWEB url="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html">GPL version 3</LIENWEB> or later.</PARAGRAPHE>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION titre="Demo">
      <LISTE>
        <ITEM><LIENWEB url="http://adopt.github.io/daxe/demo/daxe.html?config=config/XHTML_config.xml">New XHTML document</LIENWEB></ITEM>
        <ITEM><LIENWEB url="http://adopt.github.io/daxe/demo/daxe.html?config=config/XPAGES_config.xml">New XPAGES document</LIENWEB></ITEM>
      </LISTE>
    </SECTION>
    <PARAGRAPHE/>
    <SECTION titre="Using Daxe">
      <PARAGRAPHE>Daxe is using a whole HTML document, using the URL to read parameters. It can be included in an iframe to fit inside a larger document.</PARAGRAPHE>
      <PARAGRAPHE/>
      <SECTION titre="Parameters">
        <LISTE>
          <ITEM><CODE>config</CODE>: the relative path to the configuration file (required)</ITEM>
          <ITEM><CODE>file</CODE>: the relative path to the file to be edited (optional, a new document is created if it is not specified)</ITEM>
          <ITEM><CODE>save</CODE>: the relative path to the server script used to save a document (optional, the save menu does not appear if it is not specified)</ITEM>
        </LISTE>
      </SECTION>
      <PARAGRAPHE>Upon saving, the server script receives a POST request with the path of the document in the <CODE>path</CODE> parameter and its content in the <CODE>file</CODE> parameter. It replies with the text <CODE>ok</CODE> if no error occured, or a string starting with <CODE>error</CODE> if there was an error.</PARAGRAPHE>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION titre="Building and testing">
      <LISTE>
        <ITEM>Get the code from <LIENWEB url="https://github.com/adopt/daxe">Daxe on github</LIENWEB></ITEM>
        <ITEM>Install the <LIENWEB url="https://www.dartlang.org/tools/sdk/">Dart SDK</LIENWEB>.</ITEM>
        <ITEM><CODE>./build.sh</CODE> (or just <CODE>pub build</CODE> with <CODE>pub</CODE> on the PATH)</ITEM>
        <ITEM>copy the <CODE>build/web</CODE> directory on a server (here localhost, with the contents of <CODE>build/web</CODE> inside a <CODE>daxe</CODE> directory)</ITEM>
        <ITEM>run with the URL <CODE>http://localhost/daxe/daxe_js.html?config=config/XPAGES_config.xml</CODE></ITEM>
      </LISTE>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION titre="Documentation">
      <PARAGRAPHE>Although it doesn't have as many features, Daxe was designed to look like Jaxe, and use Jaxe configuration files. So Jaxe documentation can be used as well<NBSP/>:</PARAGRAPHE>
      <LISTE>
        <ITEM><LIENWEB url="http://jaxe.sourceforge.net/en/pages_jaxe-user-guide/xml-pinciples.html">Jaxe User guide</LIENWEB></ITEM>
        <ITEM><LIENWEB url="http://jaxe.sourceforge.net/en/pages_doc-config-en/intro-doc-config-en.html">Jaxe Configuration file syntax</LIENWEB></ITEM>
      </LISTE>
      <PARAGRAPHE>There is also a specific documentation for <LIENPAGE contribution="doc-config-en">Daxe configuration files</LIENPAGE>.</PARAGRAPHE>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION titre="Extending Daxe">
      <PARAGRAPHE>As with Jaxe, it is possible to create new display types for elements. Since the programming language is not the same, it doesn't work in the same way.</PARAGRAPHE>
      <PARAGRAPHE>Extensions are written in Dart. A new display type can be added by calling the <CODE>addDisplayType</CODE> function in the daxe library. Two constructors have to be provided to create a new class extending <CODE>DaxeNode</CODE> (the equivalent of <CODE>JaxeElement</CODE> with Jaxe): one with a simple reference to the element in the schema (for new nodes), and one using a DOM node to create the node from an existing document. The new class must have an <CODE>html()</CODE> method that returns an HTML element with the node <CODE>id</CODE>.</PARAGRAPHE>
      <PARAGRAPHE>Menu functions can also be added with <CODE>addCustomFunction</CODE>.</PARAGRAPHE>
    </SECTION>
  </PAGE>
  <REFXPAGES label="doc-config-en"/>
</XPAGES>